Finding Aid for the The Sigaux Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Marcel Pagnol Folders (works), journal excerpts, G. S. notes, book advertisement page, typed bibliography, periodicals, press clippings, book auction catalog page. (Box 42, Folder 4)
- Pirandello Luigi Pirandello. Folders (works), press clippings, programs, book excerpts, book advertisements, typed transcripts (radio). (Box 42, Folder 5)
- Pitoeff Georges, Ludmilla, and/or Sacha Pitoeff. Folder (works), handwritten notes (in a different hand), G. S. notes, press clippings, greeting card, journal excerpts, program, typed transcripts (radio), change of address card, black and white production photo, handwritten letter (from Sacha Pitoëff), periodical. (Box 42, Folder 6)
- Planchon Roger Planchon. Folder (works), press clippings, journal excerpts, typed transcript (radio), programs. (Box 42, Folder 7)
- Porto-Riche Georges de Porto-Riche. Folders (works), press clippings, G. S. notes, journal excerpt, printed biographical note cards. (Box 42, Folder 8)
- Rostand Edmond Rostand. Folders (works), periodical, press clippings, G. S. notes, typed transcript (radio), journal excerpts, programs, auction catalog pages. (Box 42, Folder 9)
- A. C. Albert Camus. Press clippings, auction catalog pages, journal exerpts, periodicals (la Revolution proletarienne & Livres de France), typed radio transcript, booklet (Albert Camus: 1913-1960, printed by the Cultural Services of the French Embassy). (Box 43, Folder 1)
- A. C. 4-1-60 Albert Camus, 4 January 1960 (news accounts of Camus' death). Press clippings, journal excerpts. (Box 43, Folder 2)
- Albert Husson Program, journal excerpts, press clippings, periodicals, book (La Cuisine des Anges: Comédie en trois actes, Albert Husson. Editions Billaudot, Paris, 1952). (Box 43, Folder 3)
- Mérimée Prosper Mérimée. Press clippings (including photocopy), bound journal excerpt (inscribed to G. S. by Jean Decottiguies), correspondence (from Jean Savant, typed), book and journal excerpts, G. S. notes, book catalog and advertisment pages. (Box 43, Folder 4)
- Gabriel Marcel Press clippings, journal excerpts, typed transcripts (radio), book advertisement page. (Box 43, Folder 5)
- Moravia Alberto Moravia. Press clippings, book and journal excerpts, book advertisement pages, photocopy of a typed manuscript with corrections. (Box 43, Folder 6)
- dossier rouge red dossier: Shakespeare related materials. Press clippings, book and catalog advertisement pages, G. S. notes, book and journal excerpts (including a photocopy, and an off-print inscribed by Claude Pichois), periodical, printed postcard (from Jean Perrin), typed transcript (radio). grey-green dossier: Shakespeare as well as professional theatre related materials. Press clippings, G. S. notes, book and journal excerpts (including photocopies and various biographies), various documentation relating to the Conservatoire National Superieur d'Art Dramatique, typed manuscripts (a biography of Ibsen, "Tragedies", and another by Marc-Antoine Cianfarani), periodicals, photocopy of a printed biographical note card, photocopy of a typed manuscript with corrections (L'avènment de la mise en scène moderne), newsletter ("Les Carrières du Spectacle"). (Box 43, Folder 7)
- dossier gris-vert (Box 43, Folder 8)
- Humour - 1 Book catalog and advertisement pages, G. S. notes, press clippings, book and journal excerpts (includes illustrations), typed transcript (radio), periodical, typed transcripts (articles), typed information/notes relating to an edited work about "L'Humour Medecin". (Box 43, Folder 9)
- Photocopies of journal excerpt (Box 44)
- Greeting Card (Box 44)
- Press Clippings (Box 44)
- Programs (Box 44)
- Publication (of "la Société Historique et Archéologique de Pontoise, du Val d'Oise, et du Vexin", printed in 1979) (Box 44)
- G.S. notes (Box 44)
- Exhibit catalog (for 1967 exhibit of Leon Bakst at Galleria del Levante) (Box 44)
- Newspaper/periodical (Micromégas, No. 22, 10 juillet 1938) (Box 44)
- Book catalogs (Box 44)
- G. S. notes (on Dumas) (Box 44)
- Book excerpt (Box 44)
- Small scrapbook (articles on André Antoine) (Box 44)
- Program, Theatre National Populaire 1970-71 season (Box 44)
- Un Desert Surpeuplé by Gérard Blum (Box 44)
- Trois hommes morts dans un avion vide (Box 44)
- La Chambre No. 3 by Gilbert Frank (Box 44)
- 4 Scrapbooks of Henry Bidou's articles and theatrical reviews from various French newspapers, circa 1920s-circa 1940s (Box 45)
- Programs, periodicals, journal excerpts (including several copies of a 1979 G. S. article on Henry Monnier) (Box 46)
- Press Clippings (Box 46)
- A bound copy of the rules and regulations of A. D. E. P. ("Art Dramatique Enseignment Privé") (Box 46)
- A script for a special production of Un Songe de Nuit d'Ete (A Midsummer's Night Dream, translated by Marcel Pagnol for the "Prince's Jubilee", Monaco) (Box 46)
- Change of address card (of Edmond de Linières) (Box 46)
- Bound journal excerpts (1 inscribed to G. S. by Francis Pruner, 3 inscribed by Tadeusz Kowzan, 1 by Sylvie Chevalley) (Box 46)
- Printed brochure ("Dossier Confluent: Groupe de Travail, Lille") (Box 46)
- A 1955 program of the "Ensemble Officiel de la Republique Populaire de Chine" (Chinese theatre, dance, and opera) (Box 46)
- Note cards (Box 46)
- Photocopied script of Cocteau's Orphée (Box 46)
- Auction catalog page (Box 46)
- Theatre tickets (Box 46)
- Correspondence (to G. S. from Danielle Mamontoff, UNESCO) (Box 46)
- Allais Alphonse Allais & Paul Allais. Press clippings, journal excerpts, professional correspondence (to G. S. from ? of the A. F. E. E. F. A., Association Française pour l'Étude et l'Éxperimentation des Farces et Attrapes), invitation to an event honoring "Capitain Cap", typed transcript (radio), G. S. notes, correspondence (from M. R. Raphaël ? to G. S.), poster (with text signed Albert Caperon a. k. a. "Capitain Cap"). (Box 47, Folder 1)
- Annunzio Gabrielle d'Annunzio. Press clippings, G. S. notes, journal excerpts, typed transcript. (Box 47, Folder 2)
- Aragon 1897 Louis Aragon. Press clippings, journal excerpts, G. S. notes, journal advertisement, professional correspondence (to G. S. from Jean Louis Panné of the Institut d'Histoire Sociale), advertisement for music records/albums, miniature periodical (supplement to Masses, Le Nommé Louis Aragon ou Le Patriote Professionnel by Jean Malaquais), book advertisement pages, typed manuscript (photocopy of an introduction by Hubert Juin, for Les Beaux Quartiers), b&w photograph of Andrieux (Collection Félix Potin). (Box 47, Folder 3)
- Asturias Miguel Angel Asturias. Press clippings, journal excerpts, typed bibliography, typed transcript (radio), book advertisement pages. (Box 47, Folder 4)
- Barillet et Grédy Pierre Barillet and Jean-Pierre Grédy. Press clippings, journal excerpts, periodicals. (Box 47, Folder 5)
- Barrès Maurice Barrès. Book advertisement pages, typed transcript (radio), journal excerpt, G. S. notes, press clippings, correspondence (to G. S. from Philippe Barrès). (Box 47, Folder 6)
- Baudelaire Charles Baudelaire. Journal excerpts, book catalog and advertisement pages, periodical (litterary supplement to the Revue Independante, No. 77), press clippings, G. S. notes, auction catalog pages. (Box 47, Folder 7)
- Simone de Beauvoir Simone de Beauvoir. Journal excerpts, press clippings, G. S. notes, book advertisement pages. (Box 47, Folder 8)
- Albert Béguin Albert Béguin. Journal excerpt, press clippings, G. S. notes. (Box 47, Folder 9)
- Pierre Benoit Pierre Benoit. Press clippings, typed chronology, book advertisement pages, professional correpondence (memo to Marc Lynne from Gaston Burnand, copied to Yvonne Rosso and G. S.; memo to G. S. from Yvonne Rosso; memo to G. Burnand from D. Benedite of the Guilde Internationale du Disque; note to Esménard from G. S.; letters to G. S. from R. Esménard of the Éditions Albin Michel; letter to Robert Esménard from G. S.; letter to Emmanuel Fradkin from Yvonne Rosso; from the Comité d'Action du Souvenir de Pierre Benoit), typed filmography, photocopy of a book preface, auction catalog page, photocopy of a typed manuscript, journal excerpts, booklets (Discours de Réception de M. Pierre Benoit et Réponse de M. Henri de Régnier; Inauguration de la Statue de Edmond Rostand A Cambo: Discours Prononcé par M. Pierre Benoit...; Hommage a la Mémoire du Père Sarloutte...: Discours de M. Pierre Benoit; Discours Prononcés dans la Séance Publique tenue par l'Académie Française pour la Réception de M. André François-Poncet...), typed transcripts (articles, letter {to Marcel Prévost from Pierre Benoit}), faded photocopies (of P. Benoit's response to Claude Farrère, an article, and of a handwritten manuscript). (Box 47, Folder 10)
- Bergson Henri Bergson. Journal excerpts, press clippings, typed transcript (radio), G. S. notes. (Box 47, Folder 11)
- Billy André Billy. Book advertisement pages, press clippings, correspondence (to G. S. from André Billy), photocopy of a contract (between André Billy and the Éditions de la Table Ronde), journal and book excerpts, bibliography. (Box 47, Folder 12)
- Breton André Breton. Journal excerpts, press clippings, typed transcript (radio/article). (Box 47, Folder 13)
- Butor 1926 Michel Butor. Journal and book excerpts, press clippings, typed transcript (of a speech given by M. Butor). (Box 47, Folder 14)
- Calef 1907-1968 Noël Calef. Press clippings, journal excerpts, book advertisement pages, personal and professional correspondence (to G. S. from Pierre Châtelain, Simone Veron, J. Clavel, W. Dubensky, and "Nisso" {N. Calef}), G. S. notes, typed bibliography, a typed copy of Maurice Renault's introduction to Ascenseur pour l'échafaud, a typed summary of N. Calef's Ascenseur pour l'échafaud, typed biography, 3 b&w photographs. (Box 48, Folder 1)
- Canard - presse Duck - press (relating to G. S.'s translation of Ibsen's Le Canard Sauvage / The Wild Duck). Press clippings (including photocopies), journal excerpts, programs, G. S. notes, 2 periodicals (Théâtre de la Ville), typed transcripts, invitation and ticket to a special presentation of Le Canard Sauvage, correspondence (to G. S. from Jean le Clercq), professional correspondence (to G.S. from the Théâtre de la Ville and the SACD {Société des Auteurs et Compositeurs Dramatiques}). (Box 48, Folder 2)
- Cassou Jean Cassou. Press clippings, journal excerpts, book advertisement pages, G. S. notes, printed biographical notecard, typed transcript (radio). (Box 48, Folder 3)
- Cayrol Jean Cayrol. Press clippings, journal excerpts, typed transcripts (radio), book advertisement pages. (Box 48, Folder 4)
- Céline Louis-Ferdinand Céline. Press clippings, journal excerpts, book advertisement pages, bibliographic notes, typed manuscript (Le Romancier et l'Histoire, by Frédéric Grover). (Box 48, Folder 5)
- Cendrars Blaise Cendrars. Press clippings, journal excerpts, typed and handwritten bibliographies, handwritten biography, bibliographical notes, invitation to an exposition of paintings, typed transcripts (radio), G. S. notes. (Box 48, Folder 6)
- Chateaubriand Francois René, Vicomte de Chateaubriand. Journal excerpts (including off-prints and reprinted letters), press clippings, book catalog and advertisement pages, typed transcripts (radio), G. S. notes. (Box 48, Folder 7)
- Chamson André Chamson. Press clippings, journal excerpts. (Box 48, Folder 8)
- Chesterton Gilbert Keith Chesterton. Press clippings, journal excerpts, G. S. notes, book advertisement pages, typed biography, typed manuscript (G. K. Chesterton: Homme de Lettres Anglais de l'Époque Victorienne, by Douglas Woodruff). (Box 48, Folder 9)
- Winston Churchill Winston Churchill. Press clippings, journal excerpts, book catalog and advertisement pages, typed bibliography, G. S. notes, bibliographical notes, professional correspondence (to G. S. from Odette Arnaud, to G. S. from Yvonne Rosso, and to Yvonne Rosso from G. S.). (Box 48, Folder 10)
- Agatha Christie Agatha Christie. Press clippings, journal excerpts, book advertisement pages, typed bibliography. (Box 48, Folder 11)
- Colette Sidonie Gabrielle Colette. Periodical (whole), program for a production of Chérie at the Théâtre des Variétés, press clippings, journal excerpts, G. S. notes (including typed notes), personal correspondence (from Maurice Goudeket), auction catalog pages, professional correspondence (to Jacques Brosse from Pierre Varenne). (Box 49, Folder 1)
- Comedia - 1922 Excerpts from the newspaper Comedia from the 25th of June to the 19th of September 1922. (Box 49, Folder 2)
- Conrad Joseph Conrad. Photocopy of a typed transcript (radio), journal excerpts, professional correspondence (from Éditions Gallimard to G. S.), press clippings, biographical transcript with corrections, book advertisement pages, G. S. notes. (Box 49, Folder 3)
- Courteline Georges Courteline. Journal excerpts, G. S. notes, press clippings, auction catalog pages, printed biographical and bibliographical notecards, book excerpts, typed bibliography, handwritten and typed manuscripts. (Box 49, Folder 4)
- Curtis Jean-Louis Curtis. Press clippings, journal excerpts, typed transcript (radio). (Box 49, Folder 5)
- Daninos Pierre Daninos. Journal excerpts, press clippings, book advertisement page, portion of a book cover (for Le Jaccasin), book excerpt, correspondence (from Daninos). (Box 49, Folder 6)
- Dard Frédéric Dard. Book excerpts, periodicals (2 issues of Paris Théâtre), book (Une forme du roman noir au XXe siecle: Le Phénomène San-Antonio, conference proceedings - ?), book (Conorama, by San-Antonio {Frédéric Dard}), press clippings, journal excerpts, handwritten filmography, photocopy of a list of F. Dard's theatrical works with their première dates and locations (includes television and radio productions), typed and handwritten bibliography, G. S. notes. (Box 49, Folder 7)
- Daudet Alphonse Daudet and Léon Daudet. Journal excerpts, press clippings, a large amount of professional correspondence (Yvonne Rosso to G. S., Y. Rosso to Roger Ferlet, R. Ferlet to Y. Rosso, R. Ferlet to Gaston Burnand, and G. Burnand to R. Ferlet, G. Burnand to G. S., Y. Rosso to G. Burnand, Michèle Montandon to G. S., G. Burnand to Etienne Lalou), G. S. notes, typed bibliographies, book advertisement and catalog pages, auction catalog page, typed transcript (radio), correspondence (from F. Daudet). (Box 49, Folder 8)
- Debray Pierre Debray. Press clippings (includes photocopies), professional correspondence (to Quentin Ritzen from the Société des Auteurs et Compositeurs Dramatiques), correspondence (to G. S. from Pierre Debray), a handwritten copy of a letter from Georges Simenon (copied by P. Debray), typed biography, typed transcript (conference presentation), professional correspondence (to Gaston Burnand from P. Debray), typed manuscripts (Mon Maitre Simenon by Quentin Ritzen {Pierre Debray}, a preface to Adieu a l'Enfance, l'Écriture Souveraine Face a l'Audio-Visuel, La Dyslexie de l'Enfant), handwritten manuscript (Les Nervures de l'Être, a G. S. preface/critique), typed transcripts (radio), book advertisement page, G. S. notes. (Box 49, Folder 9)
- Dickens Charles Dickens. G. S. notes, book excerpt, journal excerpts, biographical notecard, professional correspondence (to G. S. from François Vaudou of the Éditions Rencontre), typed and handwritten bibliographies, press clippings, periodicals (2 issues of La Petite Illustration), G. S. notes, book catalog and advertisement pages. (Box 49, Folder 10)
- Diderot Denis Diderot. Periodical (Les Cahiers Haut-Marnais), book excerpt, G. S. notes, press clippings, typed manuscripts, journal excerpts, typed transcripts (radio), book catalog and advertisement pages. (Box 49, Folder 11)
- Dostoïevski Fedor Mikhaïlovitch Dostoïevski. Press clippings, program (Les Possédés, Théâtre de la Ville), journal excerpts, typed transcripts (radio), biograpical information, book advertisement pages, section of a book jacket (with text by Pascal Pia), G. S. notes. (Box 49, Folder 12)
- Drieu Pierre Drieu. Journal excerpts (including an off-print incsribed to G. S. by Frédéric Grover), press clippings, book advertisement pages (Box 50, Folder 1)
- Druon Maurice Druon. Press clippings, b&w photo, book (l'Épée de l'Amitié a limited edition, contains transcripts of speeches given on the occasion of M. Druon's recieving the ceremonial sword of the Académie Française), typed transcripts (radio, and a 1973 M. Druon speech), typed manuscripts (Maurice Druon ou l'humanisme épique, Oeuvres Complètes de Maurice Druon de l'Académie Française - a summary), journal and book excerpts, book advertisement pages, invitations (one to attend the presentation of the "Épée d'Académicien" to M. Druon, the other is to a reception hosted by M. Druon in honor of the members of the Académie Française). (Box 50, Folder 2)
- Duhamel Georges Duhamel. Press clippings, book catalog and advertisement pages, typed transcript (radio), journal excerpts, biographical notes. (Box 50, Folder 3)
- Ehrenbourg Ilya Ehrenbourg. Press clippings, journal excerpts, bibliographical notes, book advertisement pages, typed transcript (radio). (Box 50, Folder 4)
- T. S. Eliot Thomas Sterns Eliot. Press clippings, typed transcripts (radio, and Preuves Informations), G. S. notes, journal excerpts, book catalog and advertisement pages. (Box 50, Folder 5)
- Eluard Paul Eluard. Press clippings, journal excerpts, typed transcript (radio). (Box 50, Folder 6)
- Hans Erni Hans Erni. Book excerpt (includes biography and illustrations). (Box 50, Folder 7)
- Faulkner William Faulkner. Press clippings, journal excerpts, book excerpt, typed transcript (articles, interview), book catalog and advertisement pages, printed photo of W. Faulkner, G. S. notes (and notes in a different hand), bibliographical notes, ink drawing of W. Faulkner by R. N. Raimbault, periodicals (magazine littéraire, and The Atlantic). (Box 50, Folder 8)
- Scott Fitzgerald F. Scott Fitzgerald. Press clippings, periodicals (2 copies of l'Avant Scène), book advertisement pages, G. S. notes (and notes in a different hand), typed transcript (radio), journal and book excerpts. (Box 50, Folder 9)
- Flaubert Gustave Flaubert. Press clippings, journal and book excerpts (including photocopies), brochure (Le musée Flaubert et d'histoire de la médecine), G. S. notes, typed chronology & preface, book catalog page, bibliography (Box 50, Folder 10)
- Freud Sigmund Freud (includes a folder on Carl Gustav Jung). Periodical (magazine littéraire), press clippings, G. S. notes, journal excerpts, typed transcripts (radio), printed biographical notecards, book catalog and advertisement pages, booklet (Cahiers de l'encyclopédie du monde actuel: La Psychanalyse de Sigmond Freud à Jacques Lacan), typed and handwritten manuscripts. (Box 50, Folder 11)
- Armand Gatti Armand Gatti. Press clippings, typed manuscripts, typed transcripts (radio), journal excerpts. (Box 51, Folder 1)
- La Gauche 10 Mai 1981 A selection of complete newspapers and periodicals regarding the election of François Mitterand and the victory of the Left on the 10th of May 1981. (Box 51, Folder 2)
- Théophile Gautier Théophile Gautier. Press clippings, professional correspondence (from Madeline Cottin to G. S.), journal and book excerpts (including an off-print), G. S. notes, book catalog and advertisement pages, printed notecards/check-out cards (include the summaries of 2 books), printed biographical and bibliographical notecards, typed and handwritten manuscript (G. S. questions about someone else's bibliography of T. Gautier). (Box 51, Folder 3)
- Martin du Gard Martin de Gard. Journal excerpts, press clippings, typed manuscripts, book advertisement pages. (Box 51, Folder 4)
- Genevoix Maurice Genevoix. Journal and book excerpts, press clippings, typed biography/bibliography, typed transcript (radio), book (Pages Choisies by M. Genevoix with a preface by Jean-Louis Bory, inscribed to G. S. by both M. Genevoix and J.-L. Bory). (Box 51, Folder 5)
- Gide 1 Th. André Gide. G. S. notes, journal excerpts, typed transcripts (radio), press clippings, book advertisement page, newsletter (Preuves Informations). (Box 51, Folder 6)
- Giono Jean Giono. Press clippings, journal excerpts, book advertisement pages, typed transcripts (radio). (Box 51, Folder 7)
- Giraudoux Jean Giraudoux. Press clippings, typed transcripts (radio), journal excerpts, book advertisement pages. (Box 51, Folder 8)
- Goethe Johann Wolfgang von Goethe. Press clippings, typed transcripts (radio), book excerpt, journal excerpts, G. S. notes, typed manuscript (an introduction by Louis Leibrich), book catalog and advertisement pages. (Box 51, Folder 9)
- Gogol Nikolaï Vassilivitch Gogol. Journal excerpts (includes scripts), press clippings, book advertisement pages, typed transcript (radio). (Box 51, Folder 10)
- Guéhenno Jean Guéhenno. Printed biographical notecards, press clippings, journal excerpts, typed biography and bibliography, typed manuscripts (G. S. article), book advertisement pages, periodical (Livres de France). (Box 51, Folder 11)
- Gombrowicz Witold Gombrowicz. Press clippings, journal excerpts, typed transcripts (radio), book catalog and advertisement pages. (Box 52, Folder 1)
- Goncourt Edmond de Goncourt. Press clippings, journal excerpts, bibliographical notes, 2 periodicals (Livres de France, Études Renaniennes). (Box 52, Folder 2)
- Gracq Julien Gracq. Press clippings, journal excerpts, book catalog and advertisement pages, G. S. notes, biographical and bibliographical notecards, typed transcripts (radio). (Box 52, Folder 3)
- Green Julien Green. Press clippings (including a photocopy), journal excerpts (including bibliography), typed transcripts (radio), typed biographical and bibliographical notecards, book advertisement pages, G. S. notes. (Box 52, Folder 4)
- Graham Greene Graham Greene. Press clippings, journal excerpts, printed biographical and bibliographical notecards, correspondence (to G. S. from Marcelle Sibon), book advertisement pages, G. S. notes and notes in a different hand. (Box 52, Folder 5)
- Guilloux Louis Guilloux. Press clippings, journal excerpts, book advertisement, typed transcripts (radio), G. S. notes. (Box 52, Folder 6)
- Hedda - presse Hedda - press (relating to G. S.'s translation of Ibsen's Hedda Gabler). Journal excerpts, press clippings (including photocopies), programs, invitation to G. S. to attend a presentation of Hedda Gabler, telegram (to G. S. from Michel Perrin), note (to G. S. from Ingrid Bergman), typed transcript (a review by Dussane), a handwritten and typed review by Maurice Ciantar, G. S. notes, periodical (Loisir, périodique de la Comédie de Caen), professional correspondence (to G. S. from the Comédie de Caen, and to G. S. from Gerard Baby), correspondence (to G. S. from Jean Bummart {Bommart ?}). (Box 52, Folder 7)
- Hemmingway Ernest Hemmingway. Press clipping, journal excerpts, G. S. notes, bibliographic notes, book advertisement pages, typed transcripts (radio, Arts et Lettres, and Preuves Infromations). (Box 52, Folder 8)
- Hennequin Maurice Hennequin. Books (play scripts): Le Coup de Fouet; Madame et son Filleul; Bébé; La Sonnette d'alarme; Mon Bébé; Vingt Jours à l'ombre (2 copies); Un Marriage au Téléphone (2 copies); Vous n'avez rien à déclarer?; Et moi, j'te dis qu'elle t'a fait d'l'oeil (Box 52, Folder 9)
- Holocauste Holocaust (includes antisemitism in general). Press clippings, journal excerpts, G. S. notes. (Box 53, Folder 1)
- Hugo Victor Hugo (includes Adèle Hugo, Léopoldine Hugo, and Jean Hugo). Press clippings, journal excerpts, auction catalog pages, booklet (an excerpt from Paul Souchon's book Le Roman Vécu d'une Jeune Fille Romantique: Claire Pradier et Victor Hugo). (Box 53, Folder 2)